# Dayeon Kim

kim4732@purdue.edu +1 (765) 694-5879 Linkedin Link Portfolio Link

#### **PROFILE**

저는최신 기술을 습득하고 배우는 것에 깊은 흥미를 가지고 있으며, 다양한 AWS 서비스를 활용해 단기간에 효율적으로 서비스를 개발하는 능력을 갖추고 있습니다. 클라우드 기반 시스템에 특히 관심이 많아 Lambda와 같은 서버리스 환경에서 어플리케이션을 구성한 경험이 풍부합니다.

최근에는 AWS Bedrock을 이용한 LLM 프로젝트를 진행 중이며, 오픈 소스 모델을 적절히 활용해 클라우드 기술과 결합한 새로운 서비스 개발에 큰 열정을 가지고 있습니다. 항상 긍정적인 마음가짐으로 새로운 기술을 빠르게 습득할 수 있으며, 이를 통해 뛰어난 역량을 발휘할 자신이 있습니다.더불어서 오픈소스 모델들과 클라우드 기술들을 결합하여 코드 수준에서 기존 모델의 성능을 고도화하거나 빠르게 서비스화하는 데 관심이 많습니다. 최근 Diffusion 을 이용한 Image Generation 프로젝트를 진행하면서, 그 가능성과 응용 범위에 대해 큰 흥미를 계속해서 이어나가고 있습니다.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Sookmyung Women's University, Seoul Republic of Korea - Mar 2021-Present

- Double major in Computer Science and BigData Convergence
- GPA: 4.2/4.5

### **EXPERIENCE**

University of Bern Switzerland - Sep 2023-Dec 2023

Studied abroad during fall semester of 2023 and took courses in Machine Learning and Big Data Analysis.

Purdue University West Lafayette, Indiana, United States - Mar 2024-Present

- Sponsored by IITP, a Korean Government Information and Communications Technology Promotion, in collaboration with Purdue University's Computer and Information Technology department
- Conducted research in FACE: Facial Attributes Control and Editing Human-Centric Diffusion Prior

#### **AWARDS**

Basel Hack Second Prize Basel, Switzerland — Oct 2023

Implemented and developed LLM model using Streamlit and Slack app to enable employees to get information on technical issues through chatbot.

AWSXStreamlit University Competition First Prize Seoul, South Korea — Nov 2022–Oct 2022

- Developed a search engine for efficient searching of start-ups and investors and investment preference analysis by using real-time collected data.
- Optimized search performance and speed using Inverted indexing structure and KNN algorithm.
- Developed in a serverless environment using ElasticSearch, Streamlit, and AWS services.

KB Kookmin Bank Software Competition Grand Prize Seoul, South Korea — Nov 2022

Uni-Dthon Hackathon first prize First Prize Seoul. South Korea — Oct 2022

#### **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

AWS x Ottogi Mentor Project Seoul, South Korea - Nov 2023

- Enabled users to take a photo of Ottogi's product and view reviews and recipes, and ask about the product through a chatbot.
- Developed a chatbot service utilizing GPT-4 and LLM models, allowing customers to obtain product information.
- Developed in a AWS serverless development for the project and managed an Elastic Database cluster for efficient data storage.
- Conducted data pre-processing and visualized product warehouse data using Kibana.
- Implemented an OCR text detection model to identify products from images.

HerHack Zurich, Switzerland — Oct 2023

- Resolved technical problems for company Kanton Aagrau by developing a B2B plastic recycling platform.
- Algorithmically generated and provided recycling cycles based on distance and plastic types when companies inquire about plastic materials.
- Utilized AWS Alexa and voice recognition AI devices by implementing AWS serverless development.

Pochak Seoul, South Korea - Mar 2023-Present

- Participated as a back-end engineer, using Spring Boot and serverless development skills.
- Contributed as a DevOps developer, responsible for tasks like CI/CD for automatic deployment and resource management.
- Currently working on the deep learning model using facial images.
- Supported as a member of the Sookmyung Women's University Entrepreneurship Support Team

## **SKILLS**

**TOEFL:** 98 - Feb 2023

AWS: AWS SAA C03

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**BoxLadder Technical support** Seoul, South Korea — Nov 2023

• Skills: Database engineering· streamlit· GPT· elasticsearch· AWS AWSxStreamlit hackathon Mentor Seoul, South Korea — Jul 2023

• Skills : elasticsearch · AWS